《超感警探》前情提要
Previously on "The Mentalist"...
十年前  被稱作血腥約翰的連環殺手
Ten years ago, the serial killer known as Red John
殺害了我的妻子和女兒
killed my wife and daughter.
自那以后我們一直在追捕他
We've been hunting for him ever since.
我們稱之為"布萊克組織"
We call ourselves the Blake Association.
組織里還有些什么人
Well, who else is in the association?
警察  法官  聯調局探員
Cops, judges, F.B.I. agents.
任何一個有秘密需要掩蓋的執法人員
Anyone in law enforcement that needs a secret covered up.
一個腐敗警察的秘密組織
A secret society of dirty cops.
血腥約翰是成員之一
And Red John's a member.
基拉·汀斯利死之前跟我說了件事
Kira Tinsley told me something before she passed.
她告訴我殺她的人  也就是血腥約翰
She told me that her killer-- Red John--
有個紋身
has a tattoo--
左臂上有三個點
Three dots on his left arm.
到底誰是血腥約翰
So who's Red John?
今天我們很高興地宣布
Today we're pleased to announce
我們終于確認了他的身份與面目
that we--we finally have a name, a face.
執法部門負責人
The director of the division of law enforcement,
蓋爾·伯特侖局長  就是血腥約翰
Gail Bertram, is Red John.
我手里有一份
I am holding in my hand a writ
聯邦法官的令狀
from a federal judge.
聯調局現在要關閉你們部門
The F.B.I.'s closing down your organization right now.
結束了  這里沒我們的事兒了
We're done. There's nothing more to do here.
你不會放棄  我不信你會放棄
You're not quitting. I don't believe it.
目前的情況我們已經無法掌控了
It's out of our hands for now.
保持聯絡  好嗎
I'll be in touch. Okay?
所有的一切  我很抱歉
I'm sorry. For everything.
里斯本
Lisbon.
很高興你能過來
Glad you can join us.
路上塞車
Traffic.
簡在哪
Hmm. Where's Jane?
他一有空就過來見你
He'll be in to see you as soon as he's able.
這邊走
This way.
請坐下
Please, take a seat.
情況真是一團糟  對吧
Boy, this is a mess, huh?
糟透了
A big mess.
-聽著  我覺得我們...  -一會兒有你說的機會
- Look, I think we all-- - You can talk later.
我能理解
Now I understand...
你們現在肯定都很害怕
You must all feel scared,
很緊張
nervous.
不知道接下來會發生什么事  對嗎
Don't know what in the hell is gonna happen next, right?
-探員  -所以我來說明下接下來會發生的事
- Agent-- - So let me explain what's next.
接下來的幾天
Over the next few days,
我們會找你們每個人談話
we will be talking to each of you...
單獨談話
Individually.
你們有權委托律師或工會代表隨行
You are entitled to bring along an attorney or a union rep,
由你們自己選擇
should you so choose.
我們為何需要律師
Why would we need an attorney?
我們考慮得長遠點  金寶
Well, let's look at this from our perspective, Kimball.
你們的上司伯特侖是個罪犯
Your boss Bertram is a criminal.
所以有可能你們也是
Makes sense that you might be one, too.
我們會非常仔細地審視你們每個人
We will be looking very closely at all of you.
如果你們有任何
If you have ever done anything
只要一點點可疑的舉動
even remotely questionable,
我們都會發現
We will find out,
然后起訴你們
and we will prosecute.
當然了  除非
Unless, of course,
你們能夠配合  那我們會非常非常滿意
We feel very, very comfortable with your cooperation.
那樣你們就有點回旋的余地
Then you got a little wiggle room.
加州  薩克拉門托  富蘭克林區
聯調局展開一場全球輯兇行動
The F.B.I. is overseeing an international manhunt
通緝著名的薩克拉門托執法部門官員
for prominent Sacramento law enforcement official
蓋爾·伯特侖
Gail Bertram.
聯調局方面證實
F.B.I. sources confirm
據信伯特侖就是臭名昭著的連環殺手血腥約翰
that Bertram is believed to be the notorious serial killer Red John,
他因在整個加利福尼亞州中心地帶
Wanted for a string of grisly murders
犯下一系列恐怖兇案而被通緝
across the California heartland.
伙計
Hey, man.
你好嗎
How's it going?
你這有公用電話嗎
Do you have a pay phone?
在那邊
It's right back there.
謝謝
Thank you.
阿里  你好啊  給我張六合彩
Hey, Ali, how you doing? Uh, give me a Pick 6...
再來一根菠蘿味雪茄
And one of those pineapple cheroots.
六合彩  雪茄
Pick 6. Cheroot.
喂
Hello?
你好  派翠克
Hello, Patrick.
我用不著捏著嗓子講話  對吧
I don't have to use a funny voice, do I?
你知道我是誰
You know who this is.
對  知道
Yes, I do.
感覺真奇怪啊  對吧
It's weird, huh?
因為我們上次...
'cause the last time we--
舉起手來
Put your hands up--
喂
Hello?
還在嗎
謝謝
Thanks.
別客氣
No problem.
喂  伯特侖  還在聽嗎
Hello? Bertram? Hello?
人人影視
YYeTs.com
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
■
僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
更多影視更新
請登陸www.YYeTs.com
■
翻譯：灰灰是菇涼  王小麥  靜靜的木頭 Michael  那時花開
超感警探
第六季
第八集
■
時間軸：Sgelibra  芝麻圓子  兜兜兜爹   校對：灰灰是菇涼
第六季
第八集
■
特效&后期：灰灰是菇涼   總監：灰灰是菇涼
沒人  長官
Clear, sir.
的確啊
No kidding.
他在哪
Where is he?
如果你問的是簡  那我不知道
If you're asking about Jane, I don't know.
你去樓上找過了嗎
Did you check upstairs?
找了
Yeah.
你也許還沒聽說
You know, maybe you haven't heard.
大約一小時前  蓋爾·伯特侖
About an hour ago, Gail Bertram
在薩城東區的一個加油站殺了一個警察
killed a cop at a gas station in East Sac.
我聽說了
I heard.
那你聽說了伯特侖當時在加油站做什么嗎
Did you hear what Bertram was doing at the gas station?
沒
No.
他在打公用電話
Using a pay phone.
猜猜他打給了誰
Guess who he was calling.
我猜是簡
I'm gonna guess Jane.
沒錯  那他在哪
Ahh. Yeah. So where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
我認為你清楚得很
I think you do.
我沒法左右你的想法
I can't help what you think.
我認為你的男朋友和一名危險的逃犯勾結
I think your boyfriend is colluding with a dangerous fugitive.
我認為他已經深陷布萊克組織中無法自拔
I think he is up to his neck in this Blake Association craziness,
可能你也是
and probably you are, too.
我不是  他也不是
I'm not. He's not.
簡無法阻止打給他的人
Jane can't help who calls him,
而且他也不是我的男朋友
and he's not my boyfriend.
真是太遺憾了  特蕾莎
It's a damn shame, Teresa.
人人都說
By all accounts...
你是個好警察
You were a good cop.
我現在依舊是
I still am.
頭兒
Hey, boss!
瑞斯比
Rigsby?
周圍安全嗎
Is it safe?
嗯  你們在干嘛
Yeah. What are you doing?
我們聽說了伯特侖今早干的事
We heard about what Bertram did this morning.
聽說聯調局的人在找我們
We heard the F.B.I. were looking for us.
所以現在是怎樣  你們就躲在停車場嗎
So what now? You're hiding in the parking lot?
我們不是躲起來  只是潛伏
No. No, we're not hiding. We're just... laying low.
我們暫時還安全
Well, we're safe for now.
至少現在還沒有下達對我們的逮捕令
There's no arrest warrant that's put out for us just yet.
他們遲早會的
Give 'em time.
簡在哪
Where's Jane?
別問
Don't ask.
她剛已經問了
She just did.
聽我說
Listen to me.
如今加調局已經不復存在了
The C.B.I. is gone now.
我們只能靠自己了  你們得保護好自己
We're on our own. You need to protect yourselves.
你們不知道簡在哪里  他在干什么
You don't know where Jane is, you don't know what he's doing,
也不想知道  明白了嗎
and you don't want to know, you understand?
明白  頭兒
Yes, boss.
-明白  頭兒  -明白  頭兒
- Yes, boss. - Yes, boss.
那就好
All right then.
但我已經不是你們的頭兒了  關鍵就在這里
But I am not your boss anymore. That's the point.
我們只能靠自己
We're on our own.
我們明白的
Yeah, we get it.
那他在哪
So where is he?
加州  薩克拉門托  威廉蘭德公園
你被通緝了
You're a wanted man.
我想也是
Well, I like to think so.
我說真的  艾伯特給你下了逮捕令
Seriously. Abbott put an actual warrant out on you.
也不是第一次了
Eh. It's not the first time.
所以你到底要不要告訴我
So you gonna tell me, or what?
哦對  伯特侖打給我了
Oh, yeah. Uh... Bertram called me.
我知道
I know.
他說了些什么
What did he say?
不管他想說什么  他那時沒時間
Well, whatever he wanted to say, he didn't have time.
為什么他還在城里
Why the hell is he still here?
他想做什么
What does he want?
我猜他會很快再打來告訴我
I'm guessing he'll call back soon and tell me.
你的手機不安全  聯調局...
Your phone's not safe. The F.B.I.--
對  他們裝了竊聽
Yeah, they have a tap on the line.
但他們還沒追蹤到
But they don't have a trace yet.
如果他們追蹤到了  我現在就早該被捕了
If they had a trace, then I'd be arrested already.
也許如此  但他們早晚會追蹤到你的
Maybe so, but sooner or later, they'll get a trace on you.
我知道
I know.
但在伯特侖打來之前我不能扔掉手機
But I can't get rid of my phone until Bertram calls.
所以事情就懸在這了
It's all very suspenseful.
他到底想干什么
What does he want?
誰
Who?
伯特侖
Bertram.
到時候就知道了
We'll see.
你在閃爍其詞
Now you're being evasive.
小鳥的眼睛圓又亮
What beady little eyes birds have.
《小恐龍》[系列童書]  你知道吧
Tiny Dinosaurs, you know?
我知道
I know.
我知道你很清楚他的意圖
I know you know what he wants.
他到底想干什么
What does he want?
-喂  -很抱歉我那時不得不掛電話
- Hello? - Oh, sorry I had to hang up on you.
今天實在太忙了
It's been a busy day.
沒關系  這個電話不安全
Yeah, no problem. You know, this phone is not safe.
我馬上再打給你
Let me call you back in a moment.
好的
Yeah.
他說什么
What'd he say?
稍等一下
Just a second.
你好啊
Hey. How you doing?
我給你一百美元換你的手機  行嗎
I'll give you $100 for that phone.
什么
Huh?
兩百美元換你的手機
$200 for that phone.
這是什么騙局嗎
What's the catch?
不是騙局
No catch.
三百美元  外加
$300 plus...
一部替代機
a replacement phone.
那好吧
Uh, okay.
哥們  我一會兒再打給你
Yeah, dude, I'll call you right back.
交易愉快
Pleasure doing business with you.
謝了  伙計
Thanks, man.
他剛才到底說了什么
What did he say?
我覺得我們應該見面好好談談
Look, I think we should meet and talk.
-就我們倆  -就像約會一樣嗎
- Just the two of us. - What, like a date?
是啊
Yes...
不
No.
聽著  游戲結束了
Look, the game is over.
我得說你我確實不分伯仲
I'd call it a very honorable tie.
但現在一切都結束了
And now that it's over,
我真的覺得我們應該好好談談
I really think that we should talk.
停戰  不帶武器  不玩花招
You know, a truce. No weapons, no tricks.
就談談
Just talk.
然后各行其道
Then we both walk away.
談談  談什么
Talk. About what?
什么都談
Well... everything.
我想我們都需要結束此事了  對吧
I think we both could use a little closure, don't you?
就在今天  現在
It has to be today. You know, now.
我時間有點緊
I'm kind of pressed for time.
我怎么知道能否相信你呢
How do I know I can trust you?
都到現在了就別膽小了  派翠克
Ah, don't be timid now, Patrick.
我有那么多機會殺你  卻都沒下手  不是嗎
I could have killed you many times, and I haven't, have I?
好吧  時間  地點
Okay. When and where?
非常好
Excellent.
半小時后弗里蒙特公園的噴泉邊見
I'll be at the Fremont Park fountain in half an hour.
不行  我不知道那個地方  中央汽車站見
No. Don't know it. Central bus station.
-北入口  -不行  那里人太多
- North entrance. - Nah, There's too many people.
而且警察太多
There's too many cops.
你知道亞歷山大公墓嗎
You know Alexandria Cemetery?
我當然知道
Of course I do.
西門那邊有個小教堂
Yeah, there's a chapel by the western gate.
行啊  半小時之后見
That--that'll do. Half an hour.
別遲到  我不能待太久
Don't be late. I can't wait around.
半小時之后見
Half an hour.
他說什么
What'd he say?
他想見我
He wants to meet with me.
這是個陷阱
It's a trap.
可能吧
Probably.
你準備怎么辦
Well, what are you gonna do?
我去見他
I'm gonna meet him.
不行
You can't.
相信我  我知道自己在干什么
Trust me, I know what I'm doing.
簡  別去  你想想
Jane, don't do this. Think about it.
聯調局馬上就要抓到伯特侖了
The F.B.I. is gonna get Bertram soon enough.
我不想他落在聯調局手上
I don't want the F.B.I. to get him.
你知道這一天早晚會來
You knew this day was coming.
就是今天了
It's here.
那我和你一起去
Let me come with you.
不行  我不想讓你牽扯進來
No, I don't want you involved.
牽扯  我早就深陷其中了
Involved? I am involved.
再也不會了
Not anymore.
我要借你的槍
I'm gonna need to borrow your gun.
我的槍
My gun?
是  你的槍  我不會開槍的
Yes, your gun. I'm not gonna use it.
就是壯壯膽
Just a prop.
特蕾莎  相信我  拜托
Teresa, trust me, please.
相信我就好
Just trust me.
謝謝
Thank you.
那邊吧
Like that way.
謝了
Thanks.
疑犯逃跑
The suspect got moved.
負責人呢  艾伯特在哪兒
Where's the man in charge here? Where is Abbott?
跪下
Get down on your knees.
把手舉到我能看見的地方
Keep your hands where I can see them.
艾伯特在哪兒  我必須得走了
Where is Abbott? I-I have to go.
好了  淡定點  伙計們
All right, take it down a notch, people.
他又不是阿爾·卡彭
He's not Al Capone.
著名黑幫老大
艾伯特  請聽我說
Abbott, please listen to me.
我看得出來你是個正人君子
I can tell that you're a man of honor.
我以我的名義發誓  我一小時之內就回去自首
On my honor, I will give myself up in an hour.
但是現在  我...  我要
But right now I just-- I just need...
只要
Just...
算了
Forget it.
別別別  告訴我
No. No, no, no, no. No, tell me.
起來
Come on.
你要干什么  你需要什么
No, what do you need? What do you need, huh?
你需要一小時
You need an hour?
干什么
For what?
你要去哪兒
Where are you going?
去見誰
Who are you gonna go meet?
不說嗎
No?
那回局里說怎么樣
Well, let's take a trip downtown, shall we?
沒事  讓她過來吧
No. You can let her go.
你好  里斯本女士
Hi, Miss Lisbon.
就算是咱們兩個警察間幫個忙  艾伯特
Do me this one favor, Abbott, cop to cop.
放他走  我發誓到時候一定把他帶回來
Let him go, and I swear I will bring him back later.
不可能
Not happening.
你們到底有什么緊急的事
And what is all this urgency I'm hearing here?
你們是跟伯特侖有約吧
You made a plan with Bertram.
是嗎  是這樣嗎
Is that it? Is that what you did?
拜托了  艾伯特
Please, Abbott.
聯調局  退后
FBI! Back it off!
-加調局  你給我退后  -怎么回事
- CBI. Back it up yourself. - What's this?
放他走  艾伯特  他什么也沒做錯
Let him go, Abbott. He's done nothing wrong.
好啊  各位
Hey, guys.
很高興見到你們
You know, I-it's good to see you.
我本來不想提的  但加調局已經不存在了
I hate to bring you down, but there is no CBI.
你們的警徽就是個玩具
That badge is a toy,
而你們只是在假扮警察
and you're all impersonating officers of the law.
隨你怎么說  放他走
Whatever. Let him go.
你是纏上我了是嗎
Are you mad-dogging me right now?
纏上聯調局了
The F.B.I.?
你說你是真的聯調局探員  有什么證據
You say you're legit F.B.I., but how do we know?
對  你們也許是布萊克組織的成員
Yeah, you could be members of the Blake Association
也不是沒可能
for all we know.
我們不是
We're not.
拿出證明來
Prove it.
你的手下里德·史密斯就是其中之一
Your man Reede Smith was a member.
你為什么不可能是
Why not you?
而且我們怎么知道簡會不會有危險
And how do we know Jane's not in danger?
太荒唐了
That's absurd.
抱歉 艾伯特探員
I'm sorry, Agent Abbott,
但是在確保他的安全之前
but it is our duty to protect this man
保護好他是我們的責任
until we're assured his safety.
放他走
Let him go.
別這樣  別這樣
No, no, no, no, no.
沒事的  放下槍
It's all right. Just stand down.
各位都放下槍  沒必要起沖突
Stand down, guys. No bloodshed required.
沒事的
It's cool.
讓他走
Let him go.
開我的車
Take my car.
長官
Sir?
就讓他走
It's okay.
謝謝各位了
Thank you, guys!
沒事了
We done?
他走了  就沒事了
He's gone. We're done.
逮捕他們
Arrest them.
把你們的槍都放到地上
Put your guns down on the ground...
慢慢地
slowly.
照他說的做
Do as he says.
去追蹤里斯本探員的車
Go track Agent Lisbon's vehicle.
是  長官
Yes, sir.
你在我車上裝了追蹤器
You put a bug on my car?
要不我們怎么能找到簡
How do you think we found Jane?
我說過認識你們這些人我很高興
I said I was glad to see you people
因為我知道你們早晚要出簍子
because I knew you would screw up
能省我不少事
and make my life easy.
這不應驗了嗎
And you did just that.
謝謝
Thank you.
逮捕她
Arrest her.
走吧
Come on.
他還沒準備好呢
He wasn't ready for it.
沒錯
No.
看啊
Check it out.
看看這個
Check this out.
你好嗎
What's up?
能幫我看會兒車嗎
Uh, could you guys keep an eye on my car for me, please?
當然了  會看好的
Sure, I'll watch it.
謝謝
Thank you.
動手
Let's go.
好了  伙計  別擔心
Yeah, man, no worries.
等等
Hey there.
不好意思麻煩你了  女士
Sorry to bother you, ma'am.
我長話短說
Uh, long story.
你愿不愿意載我一程
Uh, I need--I need a ride, if you're willing.
這里是四隊  我們看見那輛車了
This is Unit 4. We have the vehicle in sight,
停在第五大道和謝爾曼街交會處
stationary on Fifth and Sherman.
退后  先退后  他們可能就在那兒接頭
Stay back, stay back. This could be the meet.
搞什么鬼
What the heck?
四隊  什么情況
Unit 4, what's the situation?
四隊  回答  該死的
Unit 4, respond, damn it.
頭兒  里斯本車里就幾個孩子
Boss, it was some kids in Lisbon's car.
簡不在里面
Jane wasn't there.
沒有發現簡  重復  我們沒發現簡
We don't have Jane. Repeat. We don't have Jane.
是否收...
Do you co--
別再越錯越多了
Don't dig yourself any deeper.
他去哪兒了
Where did he go?
不知道
I don't know.
你們是不見棺材不落淚是吧
You guys really have a death wish, don't you?
長官  我們真的不知道
Sir, we really don't know.
長官  你居然還叫他長官
"Sir"? Why the hell are you calling him "Sir"?
別激動  "頭號公敵"
Oh, calm down, Dillinger.
約翰.格林杰是蕭條時期聯調局追捕的最著名的黑幫頭目  曾兩度越獄
我們現在是階下囚  還是識相點吧
We're under arrest here. We might as well be civil.
干嘛  你是想住好一點的牢房
Why? You think you'll get a nicer cell?
非常感謝[西語]  奧雷利奧
Muchas gracias, Aurelio.
別客氣  祝你好運[西語]
De nada. Buena suerte.
安琪拉·蘿斯金·簡
夏洛特·安妮·簡
派翠克
Hey, Patrick.
得先得搜搜你身上有沒有武器
I'm gonna need to search you for weapons.
然后你才能進去  把手舉起來
So you can go ahead, put your hands up.
試下也無妨
Worth a shot.
你可以進去了
You can go in now.
派翠克
Patrick.
謝謝你這么準時
Thank you for being so punctual.
你騙了我
You lied to me.
你不也是
Oh. Well... as did you.
我們還真是倆無賴  對吧
What a couple of scamps we are, huh?
我保證  這是最后一次騙你了
I promise that is the last lie that I will ever tell you.
先說正事
So... first things first.
你和聯調局犯了個嚴重的錯誤
You and the feds have made a big mistake.
我不是血腥約翰
I'm not Red John.
你說什么
What?
我不是血腥約翰
I'm not Red John.
很抱歉讓你失望了
I-I'm sorry to disappoint you,
但是我只是布萊克組織
but I'm just a humble foot soldier
一員卑微走卒罷了
in the Blake Association.
血腥約翰可是高層
Red John is one of the top brass.
我不是很相信你
I'm not sure I believe you.
信不信隨你  但
Well... that's your privilege, but--
但是我說的是真的
But I am telling you the truth.
你們草率得出的結論是錯的
You all just jumped to the wrong conclusion.
那么誰是血腥約翰
Okay, so who is Red John?
我不知道
Oh, I have no idea.
真的
No, h-honestly.
不知道
No idea.
組織嚴格遵循的原則是只須知道必需的信息
The association works on a strictly need-to-know basis.
如果你說的是真的
Supposing what you say is true,
那么我們完全可以在電話里說
then we could have had this talk on the phone.
但是如果我們在電話里說
Yeah, but if we talked on the phone,
那你  你可能就不會來見我了
Then you... you probably wouldn't have come to meet me,
不是嗎
Would you?
我接到命令要打電話給你
And I was told to call you,
告訴你游戲結束  安排和你見面
tell you the game's over, and arrange a meeting.
為什么
Why?
為什么要我過來
Why am I here?
請你不要以為
Please... don't think for a moment
我樂意這么做
that I am happy about this.
組織不想有遺留問題
The association doesn't like loose ends.
不想留下把柄
Just hates them.
所以
So...
動手吧  奧斯卡
Go on, Oscar.
別  別  聽著  聽著
No, no. Listen. Listen. Let's--
我們談談  等等
Let's talk about this. Just... w-wait.
我很抱歉  這不是我能決定的
Now I am truly sorry, but it is totally out of my hands.
我一直都很喜歡你  派翠克
I always liked you, patrick.
別  別  不需要這么做
No. No. This is not necessary.
我們不
We don't--don't--
什...
H-hey...wh-
謝謝  奧斯卡
Thank you, Oscar.
你可以出去等著了  就...
You can wait outside. Just, uh...
確保沒人來打擾我們
Make sure we're left in peace.
你好  派翠克
Hello, Patrick.
你好
Hi.
現在什么情況
Hey, what's going on?
格蕾斯  你在干
Grace, what are you--
別這么做
What--please don't do that.
你還不如周呢
You're worse than Cho.
他們必須告訴我們到底怎么了
They need to tell us what's going on.
他們不需要做任何事
They don't need to do anything.
我們也什么都做不了  行行好就放松點吧
And we can't do anything, so please just relax.
放松  我怎么放松得下來
Relax? How can I relax?
你有時候表現的好像你很享受無助感
You know, sometimes I think you like being helpless.
好了  我收回  別放松
Okay, fine, I take it back. Don't relax.
用額頭把車窗撞破
Just break the window with your forehead
我們就可以跳車跑了
and we'll all jump out and make a run for it.
伙計們  團結一點好嗎
Guys, let's try to keep it together, okay?
好的  很抱歉
Okay, I'm sorry.
"抱歉"
"Sorry."
莫林斯  你是本地人  對嗎
Mullins, you're from here, yes?
是的  林肯高地的
Yes, sir. Over to Lincoln Heights.
-給我弄一張薩克拉門托的地圖  -是  長官
- Get me a map of Sacramento. - Yes, sir.
車里的電腦上就有
There's one on the computer in the car.
紙質地圖
Paper map.
紙質  地圖
Paper... map.
快點去找
Come on. Let's go.
你有紙質地圖嗎
Hey, do you have a paper map?
派翠克  終于又見面了
Well, Patrick, here we are.
可憐的家伙
Poor fella.
說他聰明又傻
Smart but dumb.
他從來沒想到
It never occurred to him
我也是布萊克組織的一員
that I am the Blake Association.
你為什么要殺他
Why'd you have to kill him?
每個人都認為他是血腥約翰  不是嗎
Everyone thinks he's Red John, don't they?
所以你們兩個同歸于盡
So... it would seem a fitting end to the story
會是這個故事完美的結局
if you two were found dead together.
沒人會再深究下去
No one will look any deeper.
所以我也必須死  是嗎
So I'm supposed to die, am I?
耗了這么多年
After all these years,
是不是不太公平
seems kind of unfair.
很公平
It's totally fair.
游戲結束  我贏了
The game's over, and I won.
這可不是游戲
It's not a game.
有人輸  有人贏  這就是游戲
There's a winner and a loser. That's a game.
我可沒要玩這個游戲
It's not a game I asked to play.
即使如此  你還是玩得很好
No, but you played it very well nonetheless.
你很有趣  很有挑戰性  謝謝
You were fun, challenging. Thank you.
你肯定有很多問題想問我  對嗎
You probably have a lot of questions for me, huh?
我們多得是問的時間
We have time, if you want.
我沒有問題
I have no questions.
你是個邪惡  性變態的反社會人渣
You're an evil, sexually perverted sociopath
還很可悲地妄自尊大
with pathetic delusions of grandeur.
這就是你的本質
The rest is just details.
邪惡  性變態的反社會人渣
"Evil, sexually perverted sociopath"?
這一點我到是承認  但是
Well, I guess I have to own that, but, uh...
妄自尊大
"delusions of grandeur"?
我不承認
No.
我沒有妄想癥
I have no delusions.
我建立了這個地下帝國
I built a secret empire.
我控制著千萬人的生命
I control the lives of thousands of people.
我說的話可以決定生死
My word is life and death,
卻沒有人知道我是誰
and nobody knows who I am.
這就是偉大
Now if that's not grandeur,
不然還能是什么
I don't know what you call it.
我會說這是卑鄙的自大狂的胡言亂語
I'd call it the ravings of a squalid egomaniac.
瞧
You see?
你總是這樣沒來由地粗魯  目空一切
For no reason at all, you... you're rude and contemptuous.
這就是害死你老婆孩子的原因
That's why your wife and kid are dead.
你又有什么資格
Who are you to butt in here
在這對我評頭論足
and make obnoxious judgments about me?
你算什么
Who are you?
你算得上什么
誰也算不上
Nobody.
你以前不了解我
You didn't know me.
現在也不了解我
You don't know me.
完全不了解
You have no idea.
派  你的問題在于
Here's your problem, Pat.
你很聰明  但是太傲慢
You're a smart man, but you are arrogant.
你不能接受別人比你聰明
You can't imagine someone smarter than you.
這就是為什么每一步
Which is why I've been ahead of you
我都能搶在你前面
at every step along the way.
你有槍  想自吹自擂
You're holding the gun. You want to brag?
盡管吹吧  我不會阻止你
Go ahead. I'm not gonna stop you.
你還是不知道我怎么騙過你的  是嗎
You still don't know how I fooled you, do you?
我怎么從爆炸中逃脫的
How did I survive that bomb?
我怎么猜出你的名單的
How did I know all the names on your list?
你一直缺少的就是這個對吧  你想要有人能欣賞你
Is this what you've been missing? Appreciation?
想讓我為你喝彩嗎
Do you want me to applaud?
你完全不知道  是嗎
You have no idea, do you?
我不知道你是怎么猜到嫌疑人名單的
I don't know how you got the list of suspects.
干得漂亮
That was a good trick.
但是炸彈那事很簡單
But the bomb gag is simple.
有兩次爆炸
There were two explosions.
第一次是個震央炸彈  為了把所有人炸暈
The first was a concussion bomb, knocked everyone out.
第二個
The second
才是那個炸死哈弗內和斯特爾斯的致命炸彈
lethal bomb that killed Haffner and Stiles
你把我  伯特侖和史密斯
only went off after you dragged Bertram,
拖出爆炸傷害范圍之后才引爆的
Smith and me out of harm's way.
沒錯
Correct.
偽造你的死亡就更簡單了
Faking your own death was easy.
布雷特·帕特里奇是布萊克組織的
Brett Partridge was Blake Association.
他可以接觸到原始DNA數據庫
His job gave him access to the primary D.N.A. database.
他把你的DNA記錄
He switched your D.N.A. Records
和你留著的一具尸體的記錄對調了
with a body that you had on ice.
一具替代品
A surrogate.
你用把尸體放在汽車后備箱
And you brought the body to my house
帶到了我家
in the trunk of your car
然后把尸體放在哈弗內和斯特爾斯旁邊
and you put it alongside Stiles and Haffner.
很好
Very good.
雖然是后知后覺
Your hindsight is 20/20.
能給你看件東西嗎
Can I show you something?
當然
Sure.
面包屑
Bread crumbs?
鳥
Birds.
真聰明
Very clever.
炸彈是你犯的一個錯誤
The bomb was a mistake.
是你演的一出戲
It was theater.
我知道不管事實看起來如何
I knew that whatever the truth looked like,
與之相反的才是真相
The opposite must be true.
求你別
Please don't.
別殺我
Don't kill me.
現在你來祈求寬恕了
Oh, now you want mercy?
在你犯下那么多惡行之后
After all you've done?
你和我不一樣
You're not like me.
你是個好人
You're a good man.
殺了我  那會一直折磨著你
It'll haunt you.
我可不是在猶豫
Oh, I'm not hesitating.
我只是在享受這一刻
I'm just savoring the moment.
你就是血腥約翰
You're Red John.
我必須承認我有點失望
I have to say I'm a little disappointed.
我的上帝
Oh, my God!
救命啊  他要殺了我
Help! Please! He's gonna kill me!
我的上帝
Oh, my God!
我是警察  請你離開
I'm a policeman, and you need to leave.
先生  很抱歉  你看起來可不像是個警察
Sir, I'm sorry, you don't look like a policeman.
我是警察  照我說的做  立刻離開
Yes, I am. Just do as I say and leave right now.
-請把槍放下  -你需要離開
- Please put down that gun. - You need to go.
不管這是怎么回事
Whatever's happened here,
但是再多的暴力也解決不了問題
more violence is not the answer.
-你不明白  -先生  我當然明白
- No, you don't understand. - Sir, I do understand.
-我知道你很憤怒  -不  你不明白
- I know how angry you must-- - No, you don't,
你必須立刻離開
and you have to go now!
先生  出于良心
Sir, in all good conscience.
他是從這里走的
All right, so he started out here,
在這個小商場棄的車
and he dumped the car here at a mini-mall.
如果是你  會在哪里安排見面
So where would you arrange a meeting?
一個能夠出入自由
Someplace with easy access, in and out,
接近高速的地點
close to the highway.
-棒球場  -安保人員太多  這是哪里
- Ballpark. - Too much security. What's that?
社區大學
Community college campus.
不是  是這里
No, that, right there.
那是亞歷山大公墓
That's the Alexandria Cemetery.
簡的妻子葬在哪里
Where was Jane's wife buried?
-這和那個有什么關系  -她葬在哪里
- What does that have to do-- - Where was she buried?
亞歷山大公墓
Alexandria Cemetery.
謝謝
Thanks.
亞歷山大公墓  出發
Alexandria Cemetery. Let's go!
我的上帝
Oh, my God.
Oh, no. Oh, my God!
來人啊  救命
Help! Please!
來人啊
Help!
去哪兒了
Which way?
那邊
Over there.
B小隊  仔細搜索這邊
"B" team, canvass this side.
丹耶爾  你跟我來
Denyer, you're with me.
-馬上行動  -明白  這邊
- Let's go now. -We see. This way.
什么動靜
What was that?
怎么回事  我在跟警察通話
Oh! What's going on? I'm on the line with the police.
我就是警察  女士  我來跟他們說
I am police, ma'am. Let me talk to them.
謝謝  是這邊嗎
Thank you. This way?
是
Uh, um, yeah, well...
該死
Ah, hell.
911  請問您有何緊急情況
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
喂
Hello?
911  請問您有何緊急情況
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
求你別殺我  饒我一命吧
Please don't kill me. Let me live.
911  請問您有何緊急情況
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
求你  饒我一命
Please... let me live.
我會告訴你我怎么猜到你的名單的
I'll tell you how I got the names on your list.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我會知道是因為我是真的靈
I-I knew because I have real psychic--
眨一次眼表示不是
I want you to blink once for "no"
兩次表示是
and twice for "yes."
你是否為你殺了我妻子安琪拉
Are you sorry that you killed my wife Angela
和我女兒夏洛特而感到愧疚
and my daughter Charlotte?
很好
Good.
你怕死嗎
Are you afraid to die?
很好
Good.
想都別想
Don't even think about it.
里斯本
Lisbon...
結束了
It's over.
都結束了
It's done.
我只是想告訴你我很好
I just want you to know I'm okay.
我會想你的
And I'm gonna miss you.